Robert Loesch

https://www.linkedin.com/in/robertloesch/ https://googlecloudlab.github.io (608) 669-9900, rtloesch@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Cloud and hybrid technology thought leader and trusted customer advocate with 20+ years experience as a Technical Sales Engineer, Architect, and Developer. Driving successful business outcomes and solving customer challenges through hands-on solutions building. Ability to communicate with developers and C-level executives alike. Public speaker and mentor with a passion for continued knowledge acquisition and growth. Master's degree in Management Information Systems and MBA degree. International work experience and fluency in English and German.

RECENT CUSTOMER QUOTE (Sep 2022)

"We could not be more happy with the attention and support that we get from Robert. I told Robert yesterday that our team views him as a member of our team in almost every way and we feel like Robert returns that perspective. We believe Robert is looking out for the well-being of our company and acts as a partner in the truest sense of the word. As you know, this is very important to me! We really appreciate Robert!" - Sr. Director Cloud, Strategic Transportation Business

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Google Cloud — *Customer Engineer*, *Enterprise Accounts in WI* February 2020 - PRESENT

- Established trusted advisor relationships and owned the technical relationship with Google Cloud customers. Responsibilities include the identification and qualification of business opportunities, managing product and solution briefings, proof-of-concept work, and the coordination of additional technical resources to resolve technical blockers.
- Recommended migration strategies, enterprise architectures, migration tools and cloud infrastructure required to successfully implement a complete solution using best practices on Google Cloud.
- Conducted certification study group office hours and mentored a group of Cloud Engineers at several customers for the Google Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer certification and certified 8 engineers at my customers.
- Led the efforts for planning and coordinating the Google presence at the THAT conference with approx. 1000 attendees. Worked with marketing on sponsorship of the event and presented at the conference.
- Achieved CE L300 attestation among the first 50 CEs in Google Cloud and mentored other CEs to achieve L300. Organized a panel to guide with the Challenge Lab, presented to a group of CEs for guidance on their CE packages, and reviewed individual packages for CEs.
- Facilitating quarterly certification office hours for the Google Cloud Professional DevOps Engineer Certification for NorthAm engineers. In 2022 16 engineers that attended my office hours have successfully completed the Google Cloud Professional DevOps Engineer certification.

IBM - Executive Architect

February 2005 - February 2020

- Led a team of architects to provide an assessment of an insurance platform on IBM
 Cloud in terms of cost optimization, stability, performance, flexibility, and openness.
- IBM Global Business Services representative at a major cloud conference to advise clients and booth visitors on the Journey to Cloud and application modernization.
 Assisted with developing the storyline and demos for the event.
- Instructor and mentor for IBM internal Red Hat OpenShift training classes and assisted 26+ students to become Red Hat OpenShift certified.
- Led a DevOps transformation initiative at a large Telco provider by establishing the
 architecture and roadmap, including the use of monitoring, tracing, and telemetry
 tools to establish visibility into platforms.
- Led the infrastructure work stream and guided the development team for the IBM
 Watson Natural Language Processing component integration with a Tax Workbench at a large professional services firm.

DEGREES

MBA in General Business, University of Wisconsin - Madison, United States of America, 2003 Diplom Wirtschaftsinformatiker, (Masters in Management Information Systems), University of Erlangen-Nuernberg, Germany, 1998

RECENT EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS

Northwestern/Kellogg Chief Digital Officer Program, December 2022 - present University of Wisconsin Data & Analytics Bootcamp, June 2022 - December 2022 Google Cloud L300 CE Proficiency Attestation, June 2022

Executive Presence & Storytelling for Customer Engineers, May 2022

Mastering Technical Sales, October 2020

Google Cloud Professional Certifications: Cloud Architect, Cloud Data Engineer, Cloud Security Engineer, Cloud Network Engineer, Cloud DevOps Engineer, Cloud Developer, Cloud Digital Leader, Associate Cloud Engineer, 2020 - 2022

Certified Kubernetes Administrator, March 2020

Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Administration, Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Application Development, Red Hat Certified Specialist in OpenShift Security, 2019-2020

PUBLIC SPEAKING

UW E-Business Consortium, November 2022: Data Engineering for Predictive Analytics THAT Conference, July 2022: First Steps with Go workshop Google Cloud Serverless Summit, November 2021: Serverless real-time data processing

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Cloud/Hybrid Platforms: Google Cloud, Red Hat Openshift, AWS, IBM Cloud

App Modernization: Microservices, Containerization, DevOps, SRE

Data & Analytics: Statistical Modeling, Jupyter Notebooks, Pandas, NumPy, Matplotlib, Beautiful Soup, SQL, NoSQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Tableau, Hadoop, Machine Learning, D3, Plotly

Programming Languages: Go, Python, JavaScript, HTML, JSON